[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview of api testing purposes
and api scanning using tosca
the explanation will be done through
hands-on demonstration
api is the shorter form of application
program
interface it's working as an interface
which allows two applications to
communicate with each other through
common message formats such as xml json
etc
[Music]
let's consider this figure to understand
more on api
assume we have four different
applications sap mobile apps web portal
and billing system which are integrated
by common interface as api
[Music]
here api is working as an interpreter
each of the system interacting with each
other by sending an api request and
receiving the api response
basically each system is communicating
with apin
based on the request api routes the
messages to the target system
[Music]
the goal of api testing is to ensure
that the core functionalities of the
application work as expected without
interacting in the ui layer
to perform the api testing always we
need to take help from any third-party
tools like postman uft tosca etc
nowadays tosca is one of the best
automation tools for api testing
the main purposes or benefits api
testing in tosca are such as
api testing can be used to validate the
core functionalities even when the ui
hasn't been developed slash modified
hence testing can be initiated much
before actual functional testing ui
based is done
frequent application changes can be
tested quickly
it is easy to create and maintain test
cases in tosca
[Music]
the api testing in tosca can be done
much faster
standalone tosca api scanning wizard is
available to scan the api in the
simplest way
process flow overview of api testing in
tosca as explained through this diagram
here
api services are used to identify the
api details and functional flow for
automation
api scan wizard is used to scan the api
and create tosca modules
create test case step generate the test
cases and perform cleanup with
parameterization
run is to execute the test cases and
share the reports to stack holders
all right
now we will learn how to scan api create
basic test cases and run through the api
scan wizard
we will demonstrate the steps using the
sample tosca api
http colon slash slash web service dot
tosca cloud dot com slash rest slash
swagger slash dot slash v2
[Music]
first we will move to the api testing
tab
here all the api test automation related
options are available
we can open the api scan wizard by
opting the start api scan option
it will take few seconds to appear the
api scan wizard
[Music]
now clearing the default folder
structure
[Music]
two options for api scanning is
available in the left top corner of the
wizard
one is for file scanning ie if we have
the json file which contains the api
details
we are going to use another option to
scan the api url
we will select or enter the api endpoint
address of sample swagger application
the advanced options such as
authentication proxy can be configured
here which are not required for our case
clicking on ok button to start scanning
the api scan components are appeared in
left navigation section
the components are grouped based on the
functional modules such as off coffees
employee etc
the auth modules contains the api
related to authentication of the
application
the payload tab of request contains
request data like user and password
click on run to receive the response of
this api request for authentication
it returns the token and the expires
timestamp
the token can be used for any other
transactions
now we will check another scanned api to
retrieve all the coffee information
move to folder coffee and
get get coffee's components
here payload of request should be empty
as no input data is required
forms tab we will provide the token
number which was received during the
authentication
run to receive the responses of this api
after successful api call the status
code should be returned as 200 and the
entire coffee list will be available in
json format
similarly we can create coffee using
postpost coffee api
here we need to provide description id
and name in payload section of request
the other can be used to delete a coffee
or search a specific coffee
in each of the cases the id is the
mandatory field in payload section
[Music]
so we can get a picture that the api can
be called with data and the response can
be viewed from api scan wizard
but here the main problem is that this
components cannot be handled as a task
at test cases data cannot be
parameterized for verification cannot be
performed
it can be used for manual testing
similar to postman tool
so for api test automation we need to
move this components in the test case
section
in the next video we will create the
tosca api test case
that's all about api scan
thanks for watching this video
that's all about api scanning using
tosca
we will learn more about api test
automation approach in next video
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
we have features like youtube trends
[Music]
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query